Finding Aid for Franklin L. Parker papers, 1816-1911
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Franklin L. Parker papers 1816-1911
Parker, Franklin Leonidas, 1820-1894.
12 linear feet and 1 oversize volume
852043 Aa 2; AC
Papers of Franklin L. Parker and the Parker family of New York (State) and Ann Arbor, Michigan. Family correspondence, business papers, diaries, 1850-1893, and other materials concerning land transactions.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Herbert S. Hicks (donor no. 2288 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Franklin L. Parker was born at Perry, Genesee County, New York on March 19, 1820. In 1829, he moved with his parents to Salem in Washtenaw County. He attended a private school in Plymouth, then in 1843, he was admitted to the University of Michigan, graduating in 1847. Following, he taught school in Columbus, Ohio all the while studying law. He was admitted to the Bar in 1850 and set up practice in Ann Arbor. Parker's real interest, however, was not the law, and after 1860, he gave most of his attention to real estate investments and other financial affairs. He had extensive holdings in Saginaw, Washtenaw, and other Michigan counties. He died February 19, 1894.
The Franklin L. Parker collection relates mainly to land investments and other financial dealings, and family matters. The collection has been arranged into the following series: Correspondence; Letterpress books; Land records; and Personal and miscellaneous.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Business records.; Land use--Michigan.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1841-1850.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1851-1860.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1861-1870.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1871-1880.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1881-1890.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; New York (State); Parker family.; Michigan--Social life and customs--19th century.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.
- Correspondence
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1816, 1818 and undated 1819 (Box 1)
  - 1819 (Box 1)
  - 1832, 1839 (Box 1)
  - 1840-1911, 61 folders (Box 1)
- Letterpress books
  - 1850-1897 include diaries, 1850-1893 (Box 1)
  - 1850-1897 (Box 3)
- Land records
  - Land titles, land abstracts, and related business correspondence (Box 4-8)
  - Land records, account books; include book of mortgages, 1838-1854 for Washtenaw County (Box 9)
  - Land records, account books; include book of mortgages, 1854-1863 for Washtenaw County (Box 10)
  - Land records, account books; include journal and letterpress books of Franklin L. Parker (Box 11)
  - Record of lands deeded to Parker (Volume 1)
    (arranged alphabetically by Michigan county)
- Personal and miscellaneous
  - Notebook, 1840-1842 (Box 12)
  - Addresses, 1837 and 1846 delivered at the University of Michigan (Box 12)
  - Diploma, 1847 (Box 12)
    (transferred to the library's diploma file)
  - Legal briefs, notes, etc. (Box 12)
  - Business papers, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Law degree and state bar membership of John M. Parker (Box 12)
  - Student essays and notes, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Miscellanea; include material concerning Ann Arbor (Box 12)
  - Miscellanea, undated (Box 12)
  - Miscellanea, 1840s (Box 12)
  - Miscellanea, 1850s (Box 12)